<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryan Kullavanijaya</title>
    <description>Experiments in Life, Language, and Beyond</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:17:57 +0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 10 Jul 2020 10:17:57 +0700</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.7</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Finding your purpose</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For those following &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.calnewport.com/blog/&quot;&gt;Cal Newport&lt;/a&gt;, you might have heard that he started a podcast called “Deep Questions” to tackle the many queries he receives from readers. While trying out the first episode, I was intrigued to hear him tackle the question of life purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addressing this, Cal distinguishes between the 1980s and 1990s fairytale of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Define your passion &amp;amp; find the matching job or career&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Be happy in life&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and the ‘deep life’ equivalent from Odysseus:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Survive the hardships&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get your life back in order (finances, health, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Develop responsibility, service to others, humility, and gratitude&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter is easier said than done, but it provides a slightly clearer framework for how to find purpose and meaning. Defining an exact passion and then magically finding the corresponding job is definitely fairytale for most, so why not put in the hard work described in Cal’s ‘deep life’ model?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-06-27/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-06-27/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You'll have it our way</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In a recent &lt;a href=&quot;https://seths.blog/2020/07/it-might-not-be-for-you/&quot;&gt;blog entry&lt;/a&gt;, Seth Godin touched on the important theme of “a meaningful specific”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both as a language educator and in my work as a tour operator, I’m coming to terms with this need to offer a meaningful specific that aligns with certain principles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For example, in the ALG Thai program, we simply aren’t going to offer vocabulary lists and grammar tables. No matter how much students may demand this, our department stands for natural language acquisition through engaging experiences (comprehensible input). If we were to change that, we would no longer be offering a natural approach program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where do we draw the line between sticking to our meaningful specific and making reasonable accommodations based upon customer responses?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 25 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2020-06-25/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2020-06-25/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Language Journey: Formal Studies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Mar 6 OS / 19 NS, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While a few people grow up without any formal language instruction, many of us have had the joy (or the pain) of attending language classes. For me, I started my formal studies in junior high and continued on through university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned in my &lt;a href=&quot;http://kullavanijaya.com/2019-02-27-Language-Journey-Early-Days/&quot;&gt;previous article&lt;/a&gt;, I have been exposed to language pretty much since birth, whether through my family, interesting books, or other outlets. My first, informal, lessons were in Spanish. One of my elementary school teachers loved Spain, and she often rewarded our class by showing slideshows of the country or teaching us a word here or there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet, my formal studies officially started in junior high. I must have been about 11 years old at the time, and I tested into my school’s Spanish program. How does one test into an introductory Spanish course, you might ask? Well, my entire class had to sit for a listening examination, in which we had to listen to the same, fictitious word being repeated over and over again. The speaker, whose voice we heard on a rather dated record or 8-track as I recall, repeated something like ‘a-ho’ (along with other words) with different intonations and emphases on varying syllables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of us passed, even if we spent the entire time laughing through the session. Surely, one can imagine what a bunch of 11-year old kids were thinking when they heard “a-ho” a couple dozen times. It was probably the highlight of the semester for many of us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any case, the first few years of Spanish were a great joy to me. Our instructor provided us with textbooks, workbooks, and worksheets. I can still remember the first few lessons, which were all about greetings, sharing our names, etc. At the end of the first week, we had to practice a dialogue with a partner, and I recall hearing a classmate, T., presenting his dialogue. Instead of using the Spanish pronunciation of ‘¿Cómo te llamas?’ when asking another classmate’s name, T. made sure to speak about the animal instead. Yet another amusing moment for all involved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Over time, we progressed through other vocabulary, grammar points, and cultural notes. I was seemingly adept at memorizing all of these points and enjoyed trying to come up with unique combinations thereof. The homework was always a breeze, and it was fun to delve into the cultural notes and other extra information that we may or may not have had time to review in class.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As I progressed into high school, my Spanish lessons continued in much the same way, and I also decided to add German to my repertoire. Other classmates tried French and Latin, and I often snuck peaks of their textbooks and homework. The approach to all of these languages was largely the same: study the vocabulary, memorize the grammar, and drill them separately and together through homework, dialogues, in-class activities, and examinations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Much like in my former years, I loved the thrill of dissecting the code, bit-by-bit, and learning how others expressed themselves in other languages, countries, and cultures. Of course, very early on, I quickly discovered that both Spanish and German did not allow for literal, word-for-word translations. Such as in my ‘llamas’ remark above, it was made clear very early on that I couldn’t simply say, “What is your name?” but rather had to rely on the Spanish or German equivalents thereof (‘¿Cómo te llamas?’ and ‘Wie heißt du?’, for those curious souls).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Throughout these years, I also had the habit of going to Borders Books (when it was still in business) and spending hours upon hours delving through all of their language learning books. Whether it was Dutch, Japanese, or some other tongue, I was intrigued. I even bought a few of the books and worked through them from time-to-time at home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whether at school, at Borders, or at home, my approach had always been the same: memorize the vocabulary, memorize the grammar tables, and then put everything together. It seemed like the simplest formula in the world. Yet, I was still missing something.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I won’t name names, a family member often told me that it ‘hurt his ears’ whenever I would speak Spanish. (And he probably wasn’t the only person to think so!) As far as I could tell though, my pronunciation was always clear (if not necessarily native-like), and my grammar and vocabulary were usually spot on. It would take some years to figure it out, but one of the key things I had been missing at the time was to use my languages, not like English but rather like the languages themselves as they were spoken by the natives in their respective countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I may have gleaned how to express certain concepts (such as asking someone’s name) with the correct grammar or in a typical native fashion, my overall expression was still American, still Anglo-centric. I spoke and used both Spanish and German (along with smatterings of Japanese and other languages) as presented in a textbook (for English speakers, no less).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It wouldn’t be until university and beyond that I learned the value of reading, listening to, and consuming mass amounts of materials from native speakers. It was only then that I would move beyond encoding my English with Spanish or German words or phrases and finally learn to understand and speak more and more like a native.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the end of our second installment. In the third, we will look at my university years and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/language-journey-formal-study/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/language-journey-formal-study/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>My Language Journey: The Early Days</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Feb 27 OS / Mar 12 NS, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Language learning has been with me since as far back as I can remember. And no, I’m not talking about acquiring English from my parents. Though, that too is important. What I have in mind is a collection of experiences from my family, friends, and teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of my earliest language learning recollections is summarized in one word: Grandma. My late grandmother, due to both life circumstances and her own interests, was fluent in English, Spanish, Tagalog, Thai, and probably a few other languages she never told us about. As well, she had picked up a good deal of Portuguese, French, and Japanese, and her house would always have various language books tucked away here or there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When she wasn’t speaking English to her grandchildren, she would be using a mix of Spanish, Tagalog, and/or Thai to speak with my older relatives, Spanish or Portuguese for business, or sometimes other languages I didn’t recognize to watch TV or make long-distance phone calls. It always amazed me to see her do this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If memory serves correctly, it was my grandmother who gave me my first language learning materials. The set was a flat, but relatively large, square cardboard box, and it contained a large book and some cassette tapes. I remember the box being red in colour, and it always drew my attention. I fondly remember spending hours flipping through the pictures in the book and reading the simple words that I could at the time. I did play the cassettes now and again but found them hard to follow as a child.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Little-by-little, I picked up some phrases (numbers, greetings, etc.) through the book as well as from Spanish speakers I met through school and other sources. My grandmother would always ask me to recite the number 1-20 and other such things whenever we would get together, and she would always praise me in front of family and friends. From an early age, I learned that being able to speak a foreign language was to be applauded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway, at some point, I also discovered a black, vinyl box set of Thai materials tucked away on a bookshelf in my parents’ basement. The set had been given as a gift by some Thai family to my mother many years before I’d come along, and I’d take a peak from time-to-time to see what it contained. There were few pictures, so it didn’t hold my attention as well as a child. Yet, I was still curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To this day, I still remember thinking that if I could just memorize the Thai or Spanish equivalents of all the English words I knew, I’d have a secret code and could communicate with people in Spain and Thailand. (Of course, as a young child, Spain would be the only country in the world that spoke Spanish!)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was convinced of this fact that this was all that “foreign language” was, a special code that some people used to speak English. Yet, as an adult, I see echoes of it in many a language learning system or school. How many of us have seen teenage or adult students asking for individual words to be translated so that they can compose a stilted, artificial sentence?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I have, hopefully, outgrown this worldview, it is amusing to imagine that I considered every other language to simply be a coded language to obscure meaning. Even though everyone the world over could obviously speak perfectly fluent English, they have all opted for centuries to speak their coded versions of English instead. Perhaps, that says something about my childhood experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the end of our first installment. I will move onto my schooling years when I next have a chance.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/language-journey-early-days/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/language-journey-early-days/</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Getting Started in the Virtual World</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Finally, we’re here! After so many years of using social media, free blog sites (Xanga, anyone?), and other venues to share information, connect with friends, and make new acquaintances, it’s time to branch off to my own domain. While the exact details have yet to be formulated, I’m hoping to use this site to discuss a couple of key topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of greatest interest to the largest audience is likely to be life in Thailand. Over the last number of years, I’ve often heard from friends and others that I need to share various anecdotes in blog form. Whether that is about travel in region, experiences with local healthcare, or other interesting experiences, I have heard time and again the necessity to start writing down some of these things for others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well, being one of my great passions (and my current field of work), I hope to share some thoughts and materials here about language learning and teaching. Although I’m not a full-time Spanish or German teacher any longer, I do stay quite involved in the field and would like to connect with others that do the same. For those that already know me, it shouldn’t be a surprise that these discussions will likely be focused on the Natural Approach, Automatic Language Growth, comprehensible input, and the like. Stay tuned for more information on this front.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, of course, we’ll tackle some of the miscellaneous interests: martial arts, cryptocurrency, religion, and more. In particular, you’ll likely find information on taichokun, baguazhang, PIVX (and other privacy/anonymity tokens), and Eastern &amp;amp; Oriental Christianity. As time goes on, these may develop into blogs of their own, but let’s see what happens on my end and also what interest there is from you, the readers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the meantime, let’s kick this off with a quick publication, and I’ll get started on some actual blog posts as soon as possible!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 24 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0700</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/getting-started/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/getting-started/</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
